(Let the Strong Wind Rise)
- Nice to see you. - Nice to see you.
My gosh, it's Woo Il.
Woo Il is back.
Nice.
(Nice!)
- That was quite energetic. - Nice to see you again.
- That was a lot of energy. - His introduction got longer.
My gosh, yes.
- Your episode on our show... - Yes.
garnered a lot of attention.
What did people say?
As for my mother, she called me and said,
"Don't be cheap when it comes to food."
(My mother told me not to be cheap with food.)
(His fridge was filled with...)
(leftover food.)
(Munching)
- Yes. Your mother... - Right.
- couldn't have felt good. - Right.
(Reflecting)
All right. Let me bring in the star of Rainbow Live.
This vocalist of BTOB was recognized for his talent.
Then he was in "Goblin" and "The Golden Spoon."
And his recent drama, "The Haunted Palace," is a big hit.
- The drama is a hit now. - He's recognized as an actor...
thanks to his consecutive successful dramas.
He's an all-rounder with many talents, Yuk Seong Jae!
- Hello. - Hello.
- He's so handsome. - I knew it.
(In this popular Friday-Saturday drama,)
(he plays the male lead with a dominating presence.)
(Not only is he unrealistically handsome,)
(but he also delivers perfect acting.)
(He continues to perform as a member of BTOB.)
(The truly versatile idol star)
(Yuk Seong Jae of BTOB)
Say hello to our viewers first.
Hello. I'm a singer and an actor.
My name is Yuk Seong Jae. Nice to meet you.
I've never revealed my house on TV.
- That's what I heard. - You've never done it.
Woo Il, you know Seong Jae, right?
- Of course. - You didn't say a single word.
- He was in "Goblin." - Yes.
(A drama from 10 years ago)
(Embarrassed)
You should watch some recent dramas.
By the way, are you a regular member of this show?
- I come when they invite me. - Right.
I'm sitting here because they told me to.
- Is that so? - He came here for a meal.
- He's just... - For a meal?
- To eat? - I had many reasons to come.
- Thank you. - I was supposed to meet someone...
in Sangam-dong.
- I was just in the neighborhood. - Yes.
They told me to sit here because it'd be cool here with the AC on.
- I'll sit here for a bit and go. - Go when it's time.
You must leave when your sweat dries.
Okay.
- You must leave then. - Okay.
(Coloring to My Style)
(This place is pitch-black.)
- He sleeps in complete darkness. - Yes.
I like to keep things dark in my house.
(Pitch-black)
I bet he can even develop pictures in there.
(Stopping)
Hey, Google.
Turn on the light in the bedroom.
(Hey, Google. Turn on the light in the bedroom.)
Regarding this request, if you use Google Home,
you can gain more information...
- and complete more tasks. - I mean...
- What is this? - Try using the extension program.
Hey, Google.
Turn on the light in the bedroom.
In the context of hanok, the traditional Korean houses,
- it's located in the deepest part. - It sometimes acts up like that.
It refers to the room where the lady of the house sleeps.
Hey, Google.
Turn on the light in the bedroom.
I'm sorry. I can't turn on the light in the bedroom now.
Will you try again?
Is it trying to make you pay more?
When that happens, you get stubborn.
Hey, Google. Turn on the light in the bedroom.
I'm sorry. I can't turn on the light in the bedroom now.
You can try again or manually turn on...
(Tapping)
(In the end, he turns on the light manually and wakes up.)
Your pronunciation was pretty good.
(Half asleep)
(Let me see.)
Hey, Google.
Turn off the light in the bedroom.
(It still gives him an irrelevant answer.)
That's so stressful.
(Unhappy)
Hello.
I've been living alone for about eight years.
My name is Yuk Seong Jae. Nice to meet you.
- It's been eight years? - That's a long time.
Hey, Google.
(Tenacious)
Turn on the light in the living room.
- It's hopeless. - Isn't it better just to give up?
Sure.
- It worked here. - Sure.
(A single light turns on in the dark living room.)
- That can't be all. - Is that all?
(Why isn't this on?)
- That one didn't turn on again. - Just forget it.
Just turn it on manually.
(I'll have to do it myself.)
My house is called the Blackout House.
Well,
the color of my heart is black.
- What? - Yuk HW.
- Gosh. - I have a dark heart.
- You need a medical checkup then. - Are you suddenly...
- going through a rebellious phase? - I'm serious.
Well...
I often finish working late at night...
and have to go to sleep in the morning.
So I've always liked keeping my house dark.
That's why I decided to decorate my house with a dark theme.
As you can see, my house is quite dark.
It's like living in a bat cave.
- A cave for bats. - A cave for bats.
(Let's dive into Seong Jae's dark cave.)
It's pitch-black.
It's so black.
What?
(Why is everything so black?)
I got all of my furniture in black.
I got the cabinets and cupboards custom-made in black.
Everything is black.
Where did he find a black refrigerator?
When the new products didn't come in black,
I had to look for older models. To get them, I had to ask around.
That's a crazy commitment.
That's too dark.
(Inside the bathroom...)
My gosh.
(White fixtures were kept to a minimum.)
There's no black toilet, right?
- Please don't get a black toilet. - No, there is.
- There is? - There's a black toilet.
- There is? - There's a black toilet?
- What? Really? - But...
It's completely black.
- The designer said that... - Is it about cleaning?
it'd be hard to detect infections with black toilets.
- That's right. - Yes, that's right.
- So... Right. - Keeping it clean will be tough.
That's why I gave up on it.
Right. You kept the things that would require cleaning white.
- Right. Like the sink. - I see.
(His bedroom is also dark.)
If you open the windows, you'll get some sunlight, right?
Given the layout of the house, there are no windows.
- What? - What? How can there be no windows?
Other units have windows.
But the unit I bought doesn't have any windows on one side.
- Without the windows... - That's why I bought this unit.
- Because it had no windows? - Yes.
- But... - He likes the color, black.
To him, not having any windows is good.
But you have to ventilate the house.
That's why I only kept a small window for ventilation.
(That's why I only kept a small window for ventilation.)
What a unique taste.
(The house is dark as it barely has any window.)
It's well into the afternoon with the sun high up in the sky.
It's the middle of the day.
(Scratching)
I think the frame of the TV is also black.
- Right. I also got the TV wall... - Hold on. The TV...
custom-made in black wood.
Seriously.
- Is your underwear black too? - My underwear?
My gosh, hold on.
(Fact-checking)
He's a weirdo.
- It sort of looks black, right? - He's checking it too long.
- What are you doing? - It sort of looks black, right?
(Peeking in)
- It's black. - Why did you look at his underwear?
- It's black. - Why did you look at it?
I checked it.
He loves looking at things.
It's black with a hint of something.
- Black with a hint of glitters. - Black with a hint of glitters.
With a hint of glitters.
Seong Jae's underwear is black with a hint of glitters.
- With a hint of glitters. - Gosh.
Publish an article, please.
("Seong Jae's Underwear Has Hint of Glitters")
(Even the underwear is black in Seong Jae's cave.)
I bet plants will die within five seconds in that house.
Right.
(Leaning back)
(Spacing out)
(He doesn't move in this dark house.)
It really is dark.
I think of myself as a bear living in a cave.
I really don't do anything. I just space out.
- That's the best. - I just lie down on the sofa...
and have the TV on.
This happens when your house is dark because you can't tell time.
Right. I don't know what time it is.
When I'm home, I'm lazy like a bear.
I'd always be sleepy in his house.
(Getting up)
(He trudges to the dark kitchen.)
- He turned on the light at least. - It's bright now.
- It's bright now. - My gosh.
- Yes, this is good. - "Brightness."
- Gosh. - Yes.
(Oh, here are the lights!)
Yes. It should be bright in the kitchen at least.
- My gosh. - It must be bright in the kitchen.
- Or it will be dangerous. - That hit the spot.
It's dangerous.
(He finally summons lights.)
Your entire house looks like a stage for a play.
- Right. - Yes.
- The one with spotlights? - Yes.
(Opening)
(Squeezing out the health supplement)
I can't see things in the dark either.
I just like the dark.
I need to make sure I took the right supplements.
I turned on the lights for supplements...
or when I have to do something.
(He grabs a bottle this time.)
(Tossing)
(Munching)
That's gummy vitamin.
(He grabs a spoon.)
Why did he grab a spoon?
(What's in this small jar?)
- Is that honey? - Yes, it's Korean honey.
(A must-have item for health, a jar of honey)
For his throat health.
(Seong Jae the Bear quickly eats the honey.)
(Chomping)
The jar is white. I didn't want to see that.
So I hid it in the back.
(Then he remembers to grab his coffee.)
(Sipping)
(Come here, Wilson.)
(Where is Seong Jae headed with Wilson?)
- This room is bright. - Yes, there's some sunlight.
Gosh, look at this room.
- Gosh, his house is so dark. - Oh, my.
(He plays a sentimental track.)
All right.
(He opens the small window.)
So that's the room where you can ventilate...
- although the window is tiny. - Right.
You can't grill mackerels in your house.
- It could kill you. - The moment he grills it,
he'll pass out right away.
- He'll cough like this. - If he boils...
I bet the smell will last for six months.
If he boils snow crabs,
the smell will last for eight months in my opinion.
(He's enjoying the music, not boiling snow crabs.)
When I want to get sentimental with some music,
I use the music room.
It's the only well-lit room...
where I can enjoy a cup of coffee.
So when I listen to music, I usually go to that room.
(The music room is a great place for some sunlight.)
It looks like a prison cell.
- That's... - They look like prison bars.
They turned into prison bars.
So you can only enjoy some sunlight during your free time?
- Only model prisoners can. - Model prisoners.
- If he misbehaves, he can't go out. - He must behave then.
He has the face of a model prisoner.
The face of a model prisoner?
(Model Prisoner Seong Jae gets to enjoy some sunlight with music.)
(Focused)
(He listens to the music intently...)
(while his eyes are glued to his phone.)
(He enjoys his lazy afternoon while listening to music.)
(He gets up at the sound of the alarm.)
(He approaches the door.)
- Even his door is black. - His door is black too.
That's crazy.
He must've gotten food delivered.
Is it jjajangmyeon?
(Flicking off the light)
You should have made a request to deliver the food in a black bag.
(My plastic bag should be black too.)
Right on.
- "I'm sorry, but..." - And the rice should be black rice.
- People don't use black bags now. - "give me a black plastic bag."
Right.
(Delivering Wilson back to the dark living room)
Watch me eat.
(Safely placing it back in the corner)
(Let me sit down too.)
- You eat in the dark like that? - What?
- You must buy night-vision goggles. - Right.
(Opening the package in the dark)
(Eyes fixed on the food)
What's that?
(Satisfied)
- It's a pork cutlet. - I see. A pork cutlet.
Lunch always has to be a pork cutlet.
Why wouldn't it be?
(Chuckling)
Why wouldn't lunch be a pork cutlet?
Were you traumatized when you were little?
- Was I traumatized? - Why pork cutlets for traumas?
If he was traumatized by it, he shouldn't eat it.
- Traumas, not memories? - What?
People usually ask if it's about childhood memories.
- Who would call that a trauma? - He asked me a weird question.
Here's what I meant. You could become obsessive...
about a dish you couldn't eat when you were little.
- That's what you meant? - Right.
That's not it. Pork cutlets are men's comfort food.
It's a simple dish.
When I think about what to eat after waking up,
that's the only dish that comes to my mind.
It's a light meal too.
(He's been looking forward to the first meal of his day.)
(Today, it's a western-style pork cutlet.)
- It's a collection of good food. - That looks good.
(Placing it in his mouth)
(Humming in approval)
Yes. There are days when you crave that kind of pork cutlet.
- Right. Not the crispy one. - The cafeteria-style pork cutlet.
- Like the one from the cafeteria. - Yes.
(Leaning forward)
But isn't that too heavy for the first meal?
Is it?
- Yes. Isn't it heavy? - I...
Having greasy food as the first meal...
might upset the stomach.
Whatever it is, it'll digest better than your food.
- What do you usually eat? - It's better than your food.
I eat frozen food.
- I take food out from my freezer. - The leftover food.
- It's leftover food. - I just microwave it.
Your first meal was the hardest to watch.
- I guess so. - You drank leftover coffee too.
I guess pork cutlets are easier to digest than I thought.
- You bet. Sometimes, - Come to think of it...
- it's better than porridge. - Right.
"Right." "Yes."
(Pork cutlets are easily digestible.)
(He's having his digestible meal in the dark.)
(Yes, this is it.)
Wait. You're eating your meal without watching TV?
I'll watch something now while eating.
- Hey. - Can you just watch for a bit?
- You can't question his every move. - Okay.
"Why did you close your eyes?"
- "Why did you lean on the sofa?" - "Why did you eat?"
I'll ask at intervals.
- "Intervals." - "Intervals."
- Yes. - My gosh.
(He inhales the pasta after an interval of time.)
You're eating with gusto.
Why are you eating with gusto?
Since when did you eat with gusto?
Were you traumatized when you were little?
Were you beaten up when you didn't eat with gusto?
How could you eat with such gusto?
(He's full of questions about Seong Jae.)
(This is tasty.)
(He eats...)
(and continues to eat.)
He must really like pork cutlets if he can eat them even after...
- eating them several times. - It's true love.
(Delighted)
(That was satisfying for my first meal.)
(He cleans up immediately.)
(Sunny)
It looks like a door to paradise.
(Thinking)
(He ponders for a moment...)
(and heads somewhere.)
(He brings out a pile of boxes.)
(He plops down on the floor.)
I wonder what that is.
(What?)
(A fire extinguisher)
The renovation began when I was filming...
my drama.
I should have been here to watch the renovation progress.
But I didn't have time to do that. So I couldn't.
(Now that he has time, he'll decorate the house.)
I've been living in that house for four months now.
- That's the honeymoon phase. - Yes.
I renovated the house and decorated it in black.
I wanted to match...
all of the other items in my house to black.
- There are black ones? - Yes.
He bought a black fire extinguisher.
(What?)
What color is this?
(Putting it under the light)
Gosh, I bought one in khaki.
He did.
But he's trying to match all of the items to black.
(A disappointed sigh)
(Trudging)
Why did I buy one in khaki?
(A khaki item is added to the interior design.)
But having a khaki fire extinguisher looks pretty good there.
(After getting ambushed by the khaki prop...)
It's 3pm.
(Let me see.)
(He marches off somewhere.)
(Flapping)
(Shaking)
With this, it's perfect, Wilson.
(Pulling)
(Black Wilson is born.)
Wilson looks chic now.
Doesn't it look good? Like a limited edition teddy bear?
- Right. - Yes.
(He picks up another box after recharging on black energy.)
(Removing)
(A black clock)
- I bought a wall clock. - Gosh.
- What is this? - Everything is black.
Can you even tell time with that?
(He strides into the dark.)
(He places the black clock on the wall.)
The wall was white, so it needed some black props.
(Where should I hang it?)
You're something else.
I appreciate this kind of style.
He's all about black.
Gosh, I don't have the tools to put in a nail.
(He puts a hold on the placement of the black clock for a moment.)
I guess I'll make a trip then.
(He uses a black electric shaver...)
(and a black toothbrush to freshen up.)
(This should do it.)
(He gets dressed to go out.)
(He's ready to face the world.)
Once he goes out, the sunlight might hurt our eyes.
(He strides outside the house.)
(Rubbing his eyes)
In vampire movies, when the sun comes up,
- the vampires are in pain. - Their skin burns.
I feel that way when I go outside these days.
"Gosh, it's too bright." I can't look up at the sky.
- Because your house is so dark. - You're surrounded by darkness.
(Once he escapes from the dark house...)
I left the house when the sun was high in the sky.
It felt like the rainbow colors were unfolding before my eyes.
When you leave your house,
- it's so bright. - Right.
(The outside world is indeed sunny.)
This place is so popular.
- Seongsu-dong? - Yes, I live in Seongsu-dong.
That's my neighborhood.
It's the trendiest and the most crowded place.
- Gosh, totally. - Seongsu-dong. Yes.
There are so many stores here now.
(It's packed with people as it is a trendy spot.)
It's so hot.
(The temperature feels like 30°C, give or take.)
(The weather suddenly gets hot.)
It's so hot.
I didn't know how hot it was outside.
- So I dressed like that. - I didn't know it'd be this hot.
It's really hot these days.
I'm actually wearing...
another long sleeve shirt underneath.
- Gosh. - Oh, my.
You might die from a heatstroke.
I should've driven here.
(Pulling out)
(He's following the map to go somewhere.)
It was my first time going there.
(Since it's a hot day, he quickens his pace.)
Gosh, there it is.
(Happy to see the store)
- What is it? - Finally.
Where's he going?
(He overcomes the heat and finally arrives.)
"Outdoor."
What is this store? I've never heard of it.
Gosh, it's cool inside.
(Even the TSM seems fascinated by it.)
It specializes in selling workwear.
- I didn't know about this store. - That's a cute store.
There are a lot of industrial shops nearby.
- Right. There are many factories. - That's known as the factory area.
(Full of professional tools)
I bought a black wall clock.
(As it was a wall clock, he needed tools to put in a nail.)
I went out to buy an electric drill, so I could put a hole in the wall.
Since I own the house,
I can drill holes.
I was so excited about that.
- Yes. - That's quite the thrill.
- I love it. - It's your house.
There it is.
(He finds the electric drill he's been looking for.)
(Thinking)
Then are you going to buy that as a prop for your interior design?
- The drill? - Yes.
- That... - For his interior design?
- Hey. - I thought you were trying...
to display a cute drill on the wall.
- He said he'd drill a hole. - Yes.
Just now, he clearly said that he'd hang the clock.
- Right. - He's asking a silly question...
about drilling holes.
I'll go home after five minutes.
- You're staying here a long time. - Right.
- I've been here too long. - You stayed longer than I thought.
Excuse me.
Hello.
I just need to put a nail in the wall for a simple job.
Which one would be best for it?
That's the most popular product.
- This one? - Yes.
So I just need to make a hole in the fake wooden wall.
- It won't need to be strong, right? - Right.
I think this will do.
This will be best to drill a hole...
- in a fake wooden wall, right? - Yes.
I'll take this then.
Having a drill will come in handy. You'll use it for so many things.
- Okay. - It's your house, anyway.
(Since he's at the store, he browses other products too.)
(Grabbing)
(Immediately responding to the color of his heart)
What is that for?
I bought it to wear at home.
- What? At home? - You'll wear it at home?
- At home? - You'll wear it at home?
Wear it when your parents come over.
Your mom might not be able to find you.
"Seong Jae."
- That's... - Oh, that.
- It blocks out the noise. - I see.
- You're going to buy that? - Gosh.
It was really cheap.
It was only eight dollars.
I can't hear anything.
(Another purchase)
I should buy a pair.
(Grabbing another item)
What's that? What are the goggles for?
- They are... - They must be protective goggles.
- Yes. So nothing gets in the eyes. - I see.
But do you actually need all of them?
I don't buy things just based on needs.
(Brimming with curiosity only about Seong Jae)
Okay. Mr. Yuk.
I'm sorry.
(A stuffed bag)
(What do you think about my black goggles?)
You put them on right away.
- Gosh, you look cool. - Yes.
You look cool with anything.
That's the Seongsu-dong style.
My gosh. You look pretty good with the goggles on.
(He sets out while looking hip.)
Do you often walk around alone?
Yes. I often walk around.
But I don't usually come out during the day.
I see. Not during the day?
- It must be uncomfortable. They... - I bet people go wild...
- for him. - I like it when they recognize me.
- Really? - Yes.
We're quite similar in that regard.
(I also enjoy being in the spotlight.)
- I like getting attention too. - Yes.
- That's a rewarding feeling. - Right.
- Well... - That's how everyone feels.
(Mr. Yuk walks home with the rewarding feeling as always.)
(Staring)
(He can't look away from something.)
My gosh.
This place is new.
They're claw machines.
- I mean... - This place is huge.
- Gosh. - Oh, my. This place is huge.
- What? - I love it here.
When I see a claw machine arcade, I go in.
That's just how I am.
"Why can't I win this?"
So there's this mind game between the claw machine...
and the player, you know?
I can't just walk past the arcade without going in.
Which one should I go for?
I don't think there aren't any black dolls.
(Staring)
I see a black doll over there.
I'll go for Toothless.
- There are black dolls. - There really are black dolls.
All right. Five coins.
(They're equivalent to 5 dollars.)
Yes, you need to charge five dollars.
He'll need to spend at least 50 dollars by default.
- Are you good at this? - I'm good at claw machines.
- Really? - Gosh.
(Looking proud)
(Let me see.)
I think...
this guy here...
(Let me start with him.)
(He calmly scans the dolls...)
(while his hand carefully controls the joystick.)
I'm really confident about this.
I'm really good.
Here's a useful tip.
Just because the head is heavy,
you can't try to grab the heavy part.
This game isn't about grabbing the doll...
and dropping it off.
It's about dragging the doll.
- Right. - I see.
For big ones, you have to move them first.
I think I can win a doll only with three dollars.
I don't expect to get anything out of the first dollar.
I'll just try to see how heavy the doll is.
Then with the second dollar,
I just need to get the tail over the prize chute.
With the third dollar, as long as I have the tail over the chute,
I can pull the doll. Then it will fall into the chute.
It sounds like he plays this game a lot.
It's a piece of cake. So easy.
He sounds like an expert.
Experts have a plan before they play like him.
I recently met someone who spent 100,000 dollars on claw machines.
- Really? - He was the king of claw machines.
So how is he doing these days?
Well, he's struggling for sure.
Listen. I actually saw him play in person.
He didn't try to win it on his first try.
He came up with a plan...
- for 10 tries. - He spent 100,000 dollars?
Then he built a tower and won the doll.
- Right. - Yes.
(Another king of claw machines starts playing.)
- Let's see. - But...
- Let's see how good he is. - Yes, let's watch.
(He carefully presses the button.)
Well, his plan sounds perfect so far.
- That's how I need to drag it. - Right, you have to drag it.
You have to turn it like this.
- It should go that way. - He wasted a dollar.
He said he'd use the first dollar...
- on checking the weight. - Yes.
(Careful)
(Pressing)
This went in well.
My gosh. What?
- I knew it. It can't work. - It's gotten farther.
It's gotten farther now.
I should flip this one then.
(He changes his target to the doll near the chute.)
- That's it. Flip over. - There you go.
- That's it. - You got it. You're close.
(Surprised)
(Just like his strategy, the tail is over the chute.)
I should drag it by the legs.
I'll hook it.
(Falling)
(Disappointed)
- I can win with three more dollars. - Please insert the card.
(Determined)
(This time around, he boldly goes for the head.)
- He said not to go after the head. - That's it.
- My goodness. He's close. - He got it.
(Disappointed)
(Gosh, this is so annoying!)
Darn it.
Can't I just hit this?
(Getting spiteful)
- Right. Pick up the head... - Pick up the head.
and flip it backward.
Gosh.
I lost my patience at that point.
You have to keep calm.
(Getting mad)
Let's try 1 more time. I'll spend another 3 dollars.
Please insert your card.
He's spending over 10 dollars now.
Hit it like this.
(I'll make it happen!)
When it goes back...
(Here comes my super move!)
It can't move at that point.
(Missing)
(What?)
- I lost my patience. - You've lost your patience.
But since you're handsome,
it will be fun to play even if you don't get anything.
- What are you saying? - What are you saying?
- What are you saying? - What?
It looks like he's having fun since he's handsome.
- The whole situation? - Right.
(He focuses with his exciting face.)
Please!
He's really hooked on that.
- Another three dollars. - Please insert your card.
This is really the last game.
Right. Move it to one side.
There you go.
- Let's get it this time. - Gosh.
(Please give me the stuffed toy.)
- No! - Gosh.
- It's working. - It's working.
Gosh!
He got it.
(Yes!)
(He finally succeeds!)
He finally did it.
(He's about to fly away with joy.)
Gosh, this is amazing.
(A great achievement made with 18 dollars!)
Amazing.
(He won the black stuffed toy with his tenacity.)
Goodbye.
(I had a great time.)
Gosh, you look excited.
It felt great to come out in the morning.
(He keeps smiling during his successful outing in the day.)
- He's returning to his cave now? - Yes.
Don't go in!
(He returns to his cave.)
Why is it so dark?
- It was nice being outside. - Gosh.
Gosh, it's dark.
(He takes out something in the dark.)
It's that vest from earlier.
(He puts on his glow-in-the-dark vest.)
(He wears safety goggles...)
(and work gloves.)
(He's ready to make holes with his drill prepared as well.)
(The Black House finally becomes bright.)
The lights are finally on.
He even has those?
(He makes the finishing touch with the headset.)
I can drill holes.
(Excited about making a hole for the first time)
That feels like you're going against the rules.
Drilling holes in your house.
(He chooses the position of the hole...)
(and doesn't hesitate.)
(Drilling)
(Groaning)
- What's wrong? - It isn't going in.
Why won't it go in?
Is it a concrete wall?
This is a plaster wall!
(I definitely thought it was a wooden wall.)
You said it was a wooden wall earlier!
It felt like wood when I hit against it.
You hit against it to find out? It's not even a watermelon.
My gosh.
How frustrating.
I think it's a plaster wall.
(Looking closely)
Gosh, I can't see anything.
How do I turn on the lights?
He doesn't even call for Google as he's in a hurry.
Right.
(He even uses his flashlight of his phone.)
- Gosh, this is a plaster wall. - It's a plaster wall?
You have to use a nail for plaster walls then.
Hold on. How do I do it for plaster walls?
"Hammering a nail on a plaster wall."
(Sighing)
Place the hollow wall anchor...
- Right. You need that. - into the wall.
"Hollow wall anchor?"
(He has never heard of it.)
(That thing is the anchor?)
(Hold on.)
(Rummaging)
Let's see. I have that!
- You do? - I have that.
I asked the people around me who do interior design...
just in case.
I got all sorts of nails from them.
- That's good. - Nice.
(He starts again after finding the anchor.)
I need to use this.
(I will make it this time.)
(Drilling)
It's going in.
What?
- Is it not going in? - It feels like it's not going in.
(No matter how much strength he uses...)
It isn't going in as it's the plaster wall.
Why won't it go in?
This is bad.
(He just made the hole bigger.)
(That's terrible.)
That's so painful to watch.
I felt so annoyed.
That must be really annoying.
I'm in trouble.
(Thinking)
(Calling)
(He just scratches his head.)
- Hey, Seong Jae. - Hey, Dad.
Yes?
There's a plaster wall in my house...
and I'm trying to hang up a clock.
- There's the anchor. - Right.
I'm drilling in the anchor with the drill,
but why won't it go in?
You don't drill in the anchor first.
- You have to make a hole first. - Right.
That is when you use the anchor next.
Oh, you drill in the hole first?
- Right. - Then use the anchor?
My father used to be in the construction industry.
That is why he knows a lot.
- He's an expert. - Right.
- Your father was in this field? - Right.
(I will make it this time.)
Why do you keep putting that on?
It isn't even that loud.
Exactly.
(He uses the drill with confidence.)
What's wrong with it?
- Just hang it up on that. - Just use that.
- Right. - You should do that.
- Right. - That's nice.
That will work.
- You can hang up clothes too. - Right.
You can hang up all sorts of things on that.
- Hang up pollacks too. - Plants can be hung up on that.
Later on, you can dry radish greens on that.
- You can dry radish greens. - Right.
It can become a trend if you do it.
- Right. - Right.
- It can become a trend. - People will do the same thing.
(What's going on?)
(Why is this happening?)
- It must not have been fastened. - Right.
The hole is bigger now.
This is wood though.
- What? - What?
It was made of wood inside.
(Confused)
My gosh!
Isn't the person next door going to appear now?
- It went in. - You did it.
Gosh.
The anchor should now go in here?
- I did it! - So the hole is made...
and the anchor goes in there.
The piece goes in there.
There you go.
- Like this? - You did well.
- It looks neat. - Okay.
- I did well, right? - Yes.
- You did well. - It was my first time.
- It's the result that matters. - You can't see the hole.
- Great. - You made it.
It looks neat.
(I did it!)
It does look nice.
(It does look nice.)
Nothing is easy in this world.
Those things are seen easily.
- As everything is black? - The floor is black too.
I have so much to do.
(Grabbing)
- What is that? - There must be a lot to do.
Is it a clothes rack?
It might be.
- A clothes rack? - A carpet?
It isn't a clothes rack.
(A new black item for the black lover)
(Thinking)
- The air conditioner? - What?
The built-in air conditioner.
When I was buying it,
I really wanted a black one.
But there weren't black built-in air conditioners.
As it looked too white,
I was determined to make it black some day.
That was why I bought black contact paper.
Contact paper is easy to use.
I can just apply it like a sticker.
Contact paper...
- on an air conditioner? - You'll apply it like the sticker?
- Contact paper is hard to use. - It's really hard to use.
In matte black.
I do plaster work.
- Contact paper is hard to use. - Right.
The ceiling is done by two people.
- Right. - Everything else is done alone.
There was a time...
when my mother used contact paper over some of my furniture.
My mother is really talented with her hands.
I have her DNA.
It's not your mother doing it.
You have the contact paper DNA?
- The DNA with talented hands. - I see.
I bought it because I had the confidence.
Right.
You won't even attempt to do that without confidence.
(He prepared the contact paper with confidence.)
Challenging yourself is a good thing.
You have to give it a try if you wish to.
(He does it thoroughly this time.)
(He carefully measures the lengths.)
That must be really hard to do on your own.
Well, he said he had the contact paper DNA.
(Burning with passion)
(He makes the cuts in a flash.)
(He's focused more than ever.)
(Rummaging)
(This should work.)
What is that?
You're going to push it in as if you were working with a film.
- Right. - You're going to push it in?
- Like a scrapper? - Right.
You're going to push it in?
(The scrapper is made instantly.)
All right.
(Let's give it a try.)
(He goes on top of the chair with the contact paper he cut.)
I came up with a plan.
I decided to cut it up after sticking it on.
I will cover the whole thing up...
and cut according to each part.
Easy!
I'm curious about how it will end up.
(He applies the end part first.)
(He uses the scrapper he made earlier to push it in.)
(Sticking)
They're stuck together on all sides.
- They're stuck. - Gosh, hold on!
This is stressing me out.
(Struggling)
This is a really hard task.
(Pulling)
- What is that? - What is that?
Are you working out?
- Stop it! - What is that?
- Please stop! - What is that?
- What are you doing? - It won't stick.
- It was hard to stick it on. - Gosh.
It must be hard to stick as it's quite heavy.
Right.
I really was impressed by Seong Jae at the start.
Okay.
Why won't it stick?
(It's quite far away.)
My gosh! What was that?
- That really startled me! - You jumped?
(As my heart tells me to)
- Gosh! - Gosh!
(Flying for black)
- What is going on? - He's a lunatic.
(Closing his eyes)
(Hanging)
I must've been out of my mind. I tried to do this on my own.
This is driving me crazy. What do I do?
- Just take it off. - Just take it off.
You have to take it off.
- But I'm tenacious. - What?
(I still have to see the end of this.)
Let's apply it at least on the smooth side.
(Jumping)
Oh, gosh!
(Soaring high for black)
- What is that? - What is that?
What's wrong with this guy?
- What's wrong with you? - Why is he doing this?
Why is he doing this?
- Just why? - My gosh.
- What is going on? - I got some of it stuck on.
I did it.
- Some of it stuck on though. - Right.
(His flapping did work.)
I did it.
I did it. Gosh.
It's fascinating how he made it work like that.
(He manages to apply the contact paper.)
(He makes the cuts as planned.)
(Focusing on each move until the end)
- He looks so serious. - He should be.
He should give it a try.
(Tearing off)
I wanted to save that part at least.
- Like that? - Excluding the other parts?
- Right. - I see.
That's two-thirds of the contact paper wasted.
(I think it's done.)
(Shall I take a look at my work?)
(Snorting)
How does it look?
I'm not quite sure about this.
- That's too... - What is that?
That's just a nude gimbap.
- Is that an onigiri or what? - It's an onigiri.
I'm done.
I can't do this.
(Let's just turn on the black air conditioner.)
- Will it not work? - The sensor must be blocked.
The sensor is blocked.
What? The air conditioner won't turn on.
The remote control won't work.
The contact paper must've been too thick.
- Gosh. - That was unexpected.
(This can't be true.)
(He doesn't want to believe what is going on.)
My gosh!
It used to be a nice house.
(He compares it with the one in the kitchen.)
Gosh! The numbers are covered.
- The numbers are covered. - The numbers are covered.
- Really? - Gosh, that's bad.
I overlooked that part.
How many things are you overlooking?
Let's stop.
Let's leave it to an expert.
- What? - What?
After doing all that?
(My heart has turned black.)
It doesn't look bad though.
(Today's black items set up by the black lover)
(Even Wilson is wearing black.)
There are many different sides that I possess.
They could be seen as different colors.
They can be as the colors of the rainbow.
But when the colors of the rainbow all mix up,
they turn black.
All of my sides...
end up in black.
What is he saying?
But when they mix up, they turn into gray.
- Really? - Really?
- They turn into gray. - Really?
- Yes. - The art major corrects him.
- I wanted to say only good things. - He feels bad.
(He keeps pressing the buttons of the remote control.)
(Feeling bitter)
That looks so trendy.
(The Most Colorful Color, Black)
- Is that how it ends? - Is that how it ends?
- After doing that? - What was that?
- How does it look now? - It's still the same.
- It's still the same. - Like that?
So you don't use the air conditioner?
Well, the remote control doesn't really work.
But it does work when it's up close.
- When it's up close? - Right.
I kept watching and thought he had a clear taste.
He's doing everything he wants to do.
We've been joking around as he seemed unique,
but I think he's an extraordinary person.
Right.
You revealed your daily life for the first time...
along with your house. How was it?
- How did it feel to see me? - Right.
Wasn't it fascinating?
It's fascinating for me to see my daily life?
- What? - What?
- What are you trying to ask? - How was it?
What should I say...
when I get asked about my own daily life?
Let's just hurry up and send him home.
- Leave with Woo Il. - Let's leave together.
Leave together.
Drop me off on the way.
- Drop me off where the buses are. - Shall we leave together?
(I Live Alone)
(We Will Meet Someday)
- Did you just cry? - No.
- No? - It's the face of someone...
fighting against the world.
That's the face of a freelancer.
Gosh.
(The place he arrives at with the face of a freelancer)
(Choji Station)
Choji-dong 604?
(He heads somewhere with a destination.)
My gosh.
It has completely changed.
Really?
I got so surprised.
- So that wasn't there. - It feels like a new town.
- Gosh. - That was how it looked before?
There was a road here.
(He tries to recall his memory.)
I have come to Ansan today.
I was born in Yangpyeong,
but I moved to Ansan right away as a baby...
- Right. You mentioned that. - because of my father's work.
The place he was raised.
I entered elementary school...
and lived there until fifth grade.
I came after many years...
to meet the people I really wanted to meet.
I dressed quite formally for this occasion.
- It was a gift from Joo Woo Jae. - That one?
I wanted to look formal.
A dress shirt worn by Dae Ho...
- means a lot. - Right. It's a formal look.
This was the grass field.
The octagonal pavilion?
There was an octagonal pavilion seen from the grass field.
It was the place you lived,
but it must feel new as it has changed so much.
Yes. I couldn't find a trace of the past.
(This won't work.)
(Mother)
- Hey. - Mother.
- Yes? - When Father worked in Ansan,
- Right. - we lived in an official residence.
- Right. - Right.
Everything has changed.
Right. Everything has changed.
It was Choji-dong Complex 4.
When I purchased my house,
there was a time when I applied for a copy of my resident registration.
I always had the thought...
of wanting to visit the addresses on the list.
(The addresses that he wished to visit again someday)
You moved a lot.
- I thought about doing that too. - Right.
How long has it been since you went back?
I lived in Ansan until I was in fifth grade.
You never went back in between?
- It has been so long. - I didn't have the chance to.
- That's almost 30 years. - That's almost 30 years.
Right.
It has been around 30 years since I went back.
It must feel like a whole new world.
(Amazed)
I feel a bit weird right now.
- That was where our apartment was. - It was like this.
- It looked like this in the past. - Right. For Father's company.
- Gosh! - Gosh!
It became a whole new place.
All right. I'll call you later, Mother.
- Okay. - Bye.
You must've felt dumbfounded as it has changed so much.
It has changed so much.
It changed like this?
What?
- Is it someone you know? - Hello.
- Hello. - I'm enjoying your shows.
- Thank you. - Make sure to get married.
(Make sure to get married.)
She appeared as if he was dreaming.
- I know. - Yes.
(Get married.)
"Get married."
(Was it a dream?)
(Glancing over)
(Oh, my)
It was my first elementary school.
- There it is. - Yes.
I bet it feels strange.
My goodness.
The structure of the building is the same.
(Gasping)
The school yard looked a bit small.
At the entrance ceremony,
I held a bouquet of flowers and got my photos taken with Mom.
- My goodness. - It was "Primary school" then.
- Primary school. - Gosh.
It brought back memories.
(Looking at it now)
It made me emotional.
The school changed a lot.
(Hello.)
(He waves into the distance.)
(Running over)
(Rolling)
(Come here.)
(Panting)
Ball?
(I'll throw it back.)
(Thank you.)
Hello.
Hi.
- It's Dae Ho! - The school...
- "It's Dae Ho!" - Oh, my gosh.
(It's the man we've seen on TV.)
- Dae Ho. - "It's Dae Ho!"
I attended this elementary school.
(Cheering)
- Children are going wild. - I...
(My ears are ringing.)
- Where did you live? - I lived in that apartment.
Really?
- Yes. - How cool.
(Upon hearing about his sudden visit,)
(his juniors gather around.)
- Too many kids are coming. - You're handsome.
Please shake my hand.
(Impressed)
You're handsome. You resemble Cha Eun Woo.
"You resemble Cha Eun Woo?"
(You're handsome. You resemble Cha Eun Woo.)
The future of Korea is bright.
- Don't go! - Study hard.
- Bye! - He's as popular as an idol.
- Bye. - Don't go!
Study hard.
(Here's a special fan service.)
You can't forget such experiences from childhood.
- Bye. - Bye.
- Bye. - They're cute.
They have so much energy.
(He leaves his energetic juniors.)
Hold on. This is the place.
(Hold on.)
This is the place.
(I see!)
What?
What is it?
I remember.
My house was over there.
There's the old shopping arcade.
Gosh.
The market used to be there.
What am I going to do?
(Seeing what remains makes him emotional.)
Oh, my. My goodness.
Back in the days,
my friends and I watched the performance of The Blue here.
- My goodness. - Seriously.
- They had performances there. - The Blue was the best.
(The Blue sang passionately on the stage back then.)
(I remember.)
That's right.
Thank you.
(Proud)
(Thankfully, traces of the past remain.)
The vacant lot let me know...
that this wasn't an unfamiliar place.
The images of the past overlapped.
I felt like I had traveled back in time...
without even realizing it.
I suddenly became emotional.
That's right. I remember this place.
I hang from there and scratched myself.
- My goodness. - The apartments were low.
- Public housing apartments. - Public housing apartments.
When I was little, I thought this place was huge.
(Things did change a lot.)
I should've come a bit sooner.
Hello.
I used to live here.
- Here? - I used to live in Y Townhouse.
I attended Gwansan Elementary School.
- Gwansan Elementary School? - Yes.
- Did you attend the school? - No.
(That's too bad.)
She seemed like an alumna.
(After failing to find an alumna, he keeps walking.)
May we take a photo with you?
Shall we do that?
I attended Gwansan Elementary School.
- Really? - Yes.
I had to check just in case.
- I might know someone. - You might meet an alumnus.
- Yes. - Yes. You might meet one.
Seriously.
(We couldn't share memories, but it was a nice encounter.)
- Thank you. - Thank you.
Y Townhouse used to be here!
(Y Townhouse used to be here!)
(A forest of tall apartments fills the place.)
I have so many memories of the Y Townhouse.
My parents struggled so much.
Seriously.
I have so many memories...
of the Y Townhouse.
In retrospect, I think my family struggled a lot.
We began in a basement apartment.
From there, we moved...
to different stories. I remember that.
You remember the house in "Parasite," right?
The one with the raised toilet.
We lived in a basement apartment like that one.
- Song Kang Ho's house. - Yes.
We lived in a place like that one.
We shared the briquette furnace...
- Furnace. - with other households.
There were many such townhouses in the past.
A piano academy was here.
I could remember it.
I could remember that part of the neighborhood.
A piano academy. An art academy.
That's right.
(Everything changed.)
Five to six years ago,
- such traces remained. - I see.
It disappointed me.
Had you come sooner...
I should call my mom.
- Hello? - Mom.
- Yes? - Do you know where I'm at?
- Y Townhouse... - Okay.
and the public housing apartments are completely gone.
Oh, my gosh. Are there new apartments?
It's full of new apartments.
- I see. The memories are gone. - Everything is gone.
You know my friends from Gwansan Elementary School...
such as Jong Bae and Won Seok. Do they still live here?
- Of course. - What?
Does Won Seok's mom still run a restaurant?
Yes, she does.
I thought it'd be nice to visit her.
She'll be thankful.
- Okay. - All right.
Since I called my mom, I should visit her.
Does your friend's mom still run...
- a restaurant there? - Yes, she does.
- It's here. - You should visit right away.
Would she recognize me?
(Would she remember my face?)
It was nerve-racking...
- since it had been a while. - Of course.
- That's right. - Of course, it was nerve-racking.
- Of course, it was nerve-racking. - "Would she remember me?"
I feel like I'm watching "TV Loaded with Love."
Ma'am.
- Oh, my! Look at you! - My goodness.
- Oh, my! - She recognized him right away.
She threw her kitchen towel.
My goodness.
Look at you!
(I'm here, ma'am.)
I didn't expect to see a star here.
It's an honor to my family.
- It's so good to see you again. - You're handsome.
(He quietly hugs her again.)
(She's the mom of Dae Ho's friend, Won Seok.)
The visit was so belated. I didn't even call her beforehand.
- Hello. Gosh, Hyeon Seok. - This is Hyeon Seok's mom.
(And there's Hyeon Seok's mom as well.)
(Ahn Eun Yeong, Hyeon Seok's mom)
My goodness.
I didn't expect to see a star here.
- You're too kind. - Dae Ho.
I was...
Are you crying because you're so happy to see us?
- My goodness. - What brings you here?
I wasn't going to cry.
- Oh, no. - This brings back memories.
Why are you crying?
- Why are you crying? - My goodness.
Gosh.
I wasn't going to cry.
- I'm becoming teary-eyed too. - This brings back memories.
- This brings back memories. - Yes.
You remember, right?
- Of course. - We were young.
It was so touching.
I felt like I had gone back to my young self.
My friends' moms seemed so big back then.
But they looked so small now.
- I think I get it. - It made me feel...
many emotions.
It stimulated my lachrymal glands.
(I ended up crying again.)
- That's right. - I shed tears again.
- It's so nice... - Please take a seat.
to see you.
- Fruits. - I...
(You shouldn't have!)
- It's like a box of fruits. - It would've been nice...
to stay longer for a meal.
- But I only have a moment. - Although it's sudden,
it's so good to see you again.
- Ma'am, please have some fruit. - Seriously.
All right. You should eat.
Dae Ho, you should eat.
You still have the looks from childhood.
- Do you remember me from back then? - Yes.
- Do you remember me as a child? - Of course.
Even as a child, you were mature.
When I was young,
- I didn't play energetically. - That's right.
- You were mature. - Yes.
You were thoughtful and well-mannered.
- Ma'am, please take a seat. - Seriously.
Seriously, you were thoughtful.
- You were like an adult. - That's right.
I think she welcomes him more than her own son.
- He returned home in glory. - That's right.
Are Won Seok and the others doing well?
- Yes. They're doing well. - I see.
Won Seok has two children.
- Gosh. - Tae Ho...
has one daughter.
- Everyone is married. - Yes.
What does Min Ji do?
(Who's that?)
She became a flight attendant for Korean Air.
Really?
(Min Ji became a flight attendant.)
- Why are you so happy? - He looks so happy.
- A flight attendant? - Yes.
I have a friend named Won Seok.
He has a younger sister named Ko Min Ji.
- I see. - Yes. She was very pretty.
So you had an ulterior motive.
- An ulterior motive? - That was why you went there.
Come on.
- What was your goal? - That was why you went there.
- I mean... - You had an ulterior motive.
She must be around the age...
- to get married. - That's right.
He went there wearing Joo Woo Jae's shirt.
- He had an impure goal. - A friend's younger sister.
(A style that makes him the parents' favorite)
She has worked for 14 years.
She's like me.
- Min Ji... - Min Ji got married as well.
(Min Ji got married as well.)
- Did she get married? - She has one daughter.
Of course, she got married.
(His eyes lose their shine.)
- Min Ji... - Min Ji got married as well.
- Did she get married? - She has one daughter.
Of course, she got married.
- Min Ji got married as well. - Min Ji...
(Did she get married?)
- His tears stopped. - My tears stopped.
She's a parent now.
- Min Ji was pretty back in the day. - She was pretty.
(Just eat more fruit.)
"Just eat more fruit."
He came too late.
(He soothes the heartbreak with fruit.)
You know,
at first,
I felt a bit awkward...
- because I hadn't called before. - Right.
But seeing you made me so happy.
We didn't meet as adults.
We've known each other...
- since your elementary school days. - That's right.
- That's why... - My goodness.
- it's like that. - You brought paper.
- We have a history. - I want your autograph.
- Autograph. - She wants his autograph.
- We have a history. - He should give his autograph.
- You must be hungry. - Okay.
(I need Dae Ho's autograph.)
(Laughing)
"Stop talking and sign here."
(I can give you as much fruit as you want.)
You know, my mom...
moved to Yangpyeong...
(Eating)
You must be hungry.
(Kind)
My mom moved to Yangpyeong and felt very lonely.
But talking with you guys on the phone...
gave her strength.
She talked about you guys a lot.
- We had a lot of fun back then. - That's right.
The Moms' Association members remained close.
- Moms were young back then. - Children rarely met up.
That's right.
- But the parents remained close. - The parents.
In the beginning, you guys formed a group...
- for the children's sake. - That's right.
When I look back on it now,
I feel so thankful for the parents.
I didn't have many friends...
- back in elementary school. - That's right.
- That's right. - After the field day,
- we ate together. - That's right. We did that.
We gathered around and ate together.
(They did everything together like a family in his childhood.)
- It's an old clip. - That's from my childhood.
- There were flags of all nations. - That's right.
These days, elementary schoolers don't eat like that.
That culture disappeared.
We were very happy when you guys were in elementary school.
Every weekend,
moms and dads played soccer in the park...
and grilled meat.
I remember that.
- Yes. - It was fun.
We even visited your mom in Yangpyeong.
We did that often.
- That's right. - At the house...
- You guys met up recently. - Yes.
That's right.
That's why we're so happy to see you here.
The two of you haven't changed at all.
(The two of you haven't changed at all.)
- No way. - We became old.
- No. You guys look the same. - Time has changed us.
- You guys look the same. - My goodness.
- It's so good to see you. - It's so good to see you.
You guys seemed so tall back then.
That's right.
- You guys were young back then. - That's right.
- Our heights are matched now. - Yes.
- He's crying again. - We became shorter.
Having good memories makes you cry more.
Still, you guys are healthy.
- Both of them look young. - That's right.
That was why I was even more surprised.
It must feel so strange for them.
- You were in elementary school. - I know.
- But you became this way. - It must be shocking.
- Seriously. - "You became this way?"
I didn't mean it like that.
It's a class reunion, right?
- Seriously. - A class reunion.
- A class reunion! - I didn't know that.
- They're 2 years older. - They're 2 years older.
I'll keep crying if I stay here.
I was only visiting for a short while.
- I'll keep in touch through Mom. - Okay.
It would've been nice to eat with you if you weren't busy.
I can't believe Min Ji got married.
They will think that you're drunk.
- That's barley tea. - When you're at the airport,
see if the name on the name tag says, "Ko Min Ji."
- Then... - Does she still go on flights?
- Of course. - I see.
That's right.
Then she must know many junior flight attendants.
Of course.
(Smiling after sniffling)
(He laughs after crying.)
That's right.
You did a good job of making it sound like a joke.
I have an appointment.
Although it hasn't been long, I must get going now.
Then eat this before you go. You don't want to get thirsty.
Have a sip of pu'er tea before you go.
- Thank you. - Ma'am, please stay healthy.
Thank you so much for visiting.
- I'll keep in touch. - Okay.
- Bye. - We'll see each other again.
- All right. Let's meet again. - Bye, Dae Ho.
- I'll get going. - Okay.
You should go back inside. You don't need to see me off.
My goodness.
(You don't need to see me off.)
He's my son.
- Hello. - He's handsome, right?
It was so nice to hear her call me her son.
- Hello. - Kim Dae Ho.
Please go back inside. I'll keep in touch.
It'll be funny if he suddenly goes to the airport.
"Ma'am, I'm at the Incheon..."
- "International Airport." - I'm not at the airport.
- I'm not at the airport. - You're at the airport.
- He'll go, - "I'm here."
"Where's Ko Min Ji?"
"I just ended up coming here."
(Dae Ho arrives at a place.)
Look at his eyes.
"Where's the counter for Korean Air?"
I wouldn't know where to go without an address.
After attending Gwansan Elementary School,
I briefly attended Sigok Elementary School.
You moved around a lot.
This didn't exist when I lived here.
I should take this route. After going this way...
It's over there.
This place is very meaningful.
Mom applied for an apartment and got it...
through a housing subscription savings account.
Back then, my dad made 240 dollars a month.
But 100 dollars a month went into the deposit.
Back then, everyone struggled financially.
My parents started with nothing.
But... An apartment?
- It was the symbol of success. - It was everyone's dream.
The young couple was so excited about getting an apartment.
Back then, only the living room had linoleum flooring.
There were three rooms.
One master bedroom and two small rooms.
To save up money,
Mom and Dad bought varnish and applied it on the floor.
That was how much they cherished the apartment.
I followed my dad around when he did that.
While we waited for the varnish to dry,
- we ate jjajangmyeon. - We ate jjajangmyeon that day.
It must've been tasty.
We visited the apartment all the time...
- even before moving in. - You guys were so happy.
The neighborhood has that apartment...
as well as the school I attended.
That was why I visited the neighborhood.
(Ansan, Gyeonggi Province)
I need to go straight.
(Moved in on November 23, 1994)
I hope the apartment is still there.
I hoped the same thing.
- I think it'll be there. - I had expectations.
Yes. There was a shopping arcade.
(He passes the shopping arcade and enters the apartment complex.)
That's it.
That's right. There was a mountain.
(His memories become clearer.)
- The apartment your parents won. - Yes.
(Laughing)
(On which floor did I live?)
That was my place.
(That was my place.)
(He becomes tearful once again.)
- Why did his voice change? - Is he crying again?
Is he crying again?
It's a bit...
- I mean... - It's a bit too much.
- Seriously. - Listen.
- I'm sorry, - It's a bit...
- Kim Dae Ho. - but it isn't my memory.
Are you crying because you lost your house?
- No. - I mean...
- Why are you crying? - Seriously.
- Could it be... - Perhaps...
- He's so emotional. - we should change the perspective.
Are you crying because you sold it...
before the price rose?
You know, my parents worked themselves to the bone...
when they were younger than me...
- and bought that apartment. - You're a family man.
Yes.
(The memories of the past make him emotional.)
I didn't know that I was so sentimental.
- I get your reaction. - Yes.
- It's tear-jerking. - Yes.
- They worked hard to live there. - That's right.
He thought it'd be gone, but it was there.
He became very sentimental.
Also, I could see myself.
- When I was a child, - From childhood?
I went to school from there.
(Taking photos)
My dad worked so hard.
My dad was working at a textile company...
when he got into an accident.
He was very sick.
There were rollers for dying the fabric.
My dad was wearing work clothes.
His work clothes got caught in the rollers.
Oh, no.
- So... - It could've been lethal.
It was so dangerous.
Thankfully, his colleague turned off the rollers.
So he only cracked his ribs.
That accident could've cost him his life.
I think my dad realized it at that moment.
"While work is important,"
"what's the use of it if I can't remain healthy?"
My father's hometown is Yangpyeong.
All of family members live in Yangpyeong.
"I'll farm there..."
"and live without any greed." With that thought,
he decided to move there.
I still remember how much my parents struggled back then.
(On his way out after seeing the apartment of his memories)
(Trudging)
I think my mom sold the apartment...
through one of these real estate offices.
I should go and ask.
A real estate office?
Hello. I have a question.
Have you run this real estate office for many years?
(Nodding)
I remember how my mom sold the apartment...
through one of these real estate offices...
before moving elsewhere.
You don't keep those records, do you?
I do keep them.
Even the old ones?
I lived in...
- What? - It was fascinating.
All right. I was curious,
so I got a copy of the family register.
I wanted to see if you had the record.
You even have the very old records.
- Gosh, that's... - It's an old ledger.
It's handwritten.
- He has records from that time? - How cool.
We made a report on moving on November 17, 1994.
So it must've happened afterward.
These records are from 1994.
- I see. - Gosh, are they from 1994?
Here it is.
I was so surprised.
Kim Seok Geun.
It's 418-5357.
(Even after 30 years, his dad's name is on the ledger.)
I can't believe it.
That's my dad.
You really cherish your memories.
Back then, you...
You made a deal with my dad.
The real estate office wasn't here.
- It was over there. - That's right.
It was a long time ago.
My mom thought...
that her children would live in Seoul...
for their universities or such...
even after moving to Yangpyeong.
- So we held on to the apartment. - She held onto it until the end.
- It was her house. - But later on,
living in the countryside became difficult...
and they needed the money.
- So she sold it. - She sold it.
- She sold it after two years. - My goodness.
- Thank you. - Don't mention it.
- Thank you. - All right.
I asked just in case.
- Please stay healthy. - Okay.
- Thank you. - It was nice meeting you.
Thank you.
(He found a trace of his dad from 30 years ago.)
I didn't expect to see my dad's name there.
It really felt like I was traveling back in time.
- I can't believe there are records. - I got goosebumps.
- How fascinating. - It was fascinating indeed.
(He walks down the street as if he was traveling back in time.)
(Staring)
Back then, they were doing construction work here.
What?
Apartments popped up like they do in a new town.
- I see. - So an elementary school...
- was new as well. - That's right.
- That's right. - There were so many students...
that the classes were divided into the morning and afternoon ones.
- My goodness. - Really?
- There were so many kids back then. - Seriously.
That's right.
I think my classroom was on the second floor.
(It's another elementary school Dae Ho attended in 1995.)
That's right.
It really brings back memories.
Hello.
Thank you.
(Absorbed in memories, he gets into a taxi.)
Maybe that's a taxi you rode in the past.
No.
- That's an electric car. - "Sir, do you know me?"
- That's an electric car. - Then he'll hug the driver and cry.
(Sniffling)
Is he crying again?
(Staring)
How many more times will you cry from now on?
- I'm curious. - Knowing that will put me at ease.
(The crybaby, Dae Ho feels embarrassed.)
(His eyes turn teary again.)
(He heads over to a place with his teary eyes.)
I'm on my way to meet someone precious...
that I really missed.
Today, I'll visit my former teacher...
for the 1st time in 30 years.
After my family moved in an apartment, I attended...
Sigok Elementary School.
He taught me then.
- Really? - I see.
I've only known him for four months.
My dad got into an accident shortly after we moved there,
so we ended up going to Yangpyeong right away.
To my homeroom teacher of the new school,
he sent a letter.
- "He's like this as a student." - The duration isn't important.
I didn't know about it back then.
I only heard about it much later.
"There isn't a teacher like him. You should visit him sometime."
I've lived with that memory for over 30 years.
Yes. 30 years.
- He's a true teacher. - "I'll visit him some day."
(He's on his way to meet his teacher after 30 years.)
You look a bit nervous.
- A bit. - Right?
It was my 1st time seeing him after 30 years.
- Does he still work? - He still works.
- Really? - That's incredible.
- Is this my destination? - Yes.
Thank you.
- Thank you, sir. - All right.
Since he still worked as a teacher,
I went to see him around the time the school ended.
(Standing in front of his former teacher's school,)
He must be nervous.
(Dae Ho waits without a word.)
You're handsome.
(Smiling)
- You're handsome. - Hello.
- Hello. - He can't focus on those words.
He looks nervous.
(He can't ease the nerves.)
(Sucking in a breath)
(Breathing out)
(He takes deep breaths.)
(What does his teacher look like now?)
I'd recognize him on the street.
I still remember his face.
(I still remember his face.)
If I remember correctly, he was very thin.
He was a young teacher with tanned skin.
He wore big glasses with round lenses.
He always smiled like this.
It deepened his laugh lines.
I was a very quiet student.
He always asked me what I was doing.
He stayed by my side like a friend.
You were an introverted student.
(To an introverted student, the teacher was like a friend.)
I was quiet.
I can recognize him right away.
(He missed his teacher.)
Dae Ho is quite nervous.
(His heart beats fast.)
(Sputtering)
(He becomes more nervous as he waits for his teacher.)
(Laughing)
- Dae Ho recognized him. - Dae Ho recognized him right away.
Dae Ho recognized him.
Mr. Park.
My goodness.
- Gosh, he hasn't changed at all. - He hasn't changed at all.
- He became emotional too. - That's right.
(He meets his teacher again after 30 years.)
Mr. Park.
(Bowing)
- Hey. - Do you remember me?
(Nodding)
It has been 30 years.
I should've kept in touch.
- I'm sorry. - Don't be.
I felt so bad for you.
(Don't say that, Mr. Park.)
(His words contain a teacher's love.)
You were on "New Recruit" back in 2011.
- He watched it. - "Sunday Night."
He watched everything.
His name is Park Jeom Seok.
You might think,
"How would you remember someone you've known for four months?"
But I have very special memories about him.
That was why I visited him today.
On the Office of Education website, you can find a teacher...
through his or her name.
If the teacher agrees to it,
- they connect you to him or her. - I see.
- Through that process, - I had no idea.
I could thankfully find him.
He remembered me.
- It's so nice to meet your teacher. - That's right.
I didn't know about that method.
I should contact my teacher.
- Teachers always remain there. - That's right.
- We go to different places. - That's right.
When Mr. Park walked toward me,
I could hear...
my voice as a child.
I could hear my voice as a child.
I said, "Mr. Park." Now,
it sounds like, "Mr. Park."
- But I heard the voice... - Yes.
- I had in elementary school. - Yes.
That brought tears to my eyes.
In that short moment,
I became an elementary schooler.
- He became a child. - That's right.
- He went back to the past. - His school days.
I couldn't hold back my tears.
Mr. Park.
(I couldn't hold back my tears.)
I felt so bad.
But he hadn't changed at all.
(In an unchanged state, his teacher welcomed him.)
- He remained the same. - He really did.
(Snorting)
(He becomes emotional again.)
It's andropause.
That's right. I think...
you should dye your hair.
(Kian84 cracks a joke.)
When I heard my own voice,
I became emotional.
That's right.
(Dae Ho tears up like a child before his teacher.)
Yes.
You know, I found out later...
that you wrote a letter to my homeroom teacher...
of my new school.
He was like, "How did you have such a nice teacher?"
You wrote, "Please take good care of Dae Ho."
You wrote a letter.
My new homeroom teacher told me about it.
"You should visit him some day in the future."
That was why I contacted you.
You were still working as a teacher.
(It's so nice to see you again.)
We're too close to the school, so let's start walking.
I reserved a table at a nearby restaurant.
I just assumed that you wouldn't have had dinner.
I haven't had dinner.
Mr. Park.
To be honest, I told myself...
that I wouldn't cry.
But you haven't changed at all.
- Do you remember how I looked? - You still look the same.
You still look the same.
I recognized you right away.
How old were you back then?
It was my 1st school, so I was 25 or 26 years old.
- Oh, my. - My goodness.
- You were 25 years old. - He was 25 or 26 years old.
You were born in 1984.
- That's right. I was born in 1984. - I was born in 1970.
Back then, he was a rookie teacher.
He was a rookie teacher.
I was his first student.
- I see. - Of course, he remembers you.
Back then, you were a young student...
in your teenage years.
I'm 42 years old now.
(Time passed so quickly.)
Seriously.
- This is the restaurant. - I missed you a lot.
I'll calm down and come to my senses.
I'll come to my senses.
(I'll stop crying.)
Hello.
(He arrives at a restaurant he has made a reservation at.)
- It's a Chinese restaurant. - A Chinese restaurant.
- It's nice. It's perfect. - That's right.
It suits the sentimentality of the past.
- That's right. Yes. - There's something better though.
- Again, it's good to see you. - Dae Ho.
- It has been so long. - I could see only you.
- It has been so long. - It has always been like that.
I could see only you on TV.
(The teacher and student are still touched that they met.)
Let's order first.
- Are you okay with Chinese food? - I'm okay with anything.
This one, this one, and this one.
- He ordered many dishes. - Yes.
I made money diligently for this day.
It's the best feeling in the world.
Mr. Park, you haven't changed at all.
If I keep talking, I'll cry again. Mr. Park,
I brought photos.
You'll be surprised when you see them.
This is the photo you took.
- March 31. - That's right.
It was just after the beginning of the new semester.
Gosh, you were so handsome.
He has nice looks.
- Dae Ho is handsome. - That's right.
- He's the popular type. - He's the popular type.
- Yes. - I remember...
how you stood before me and snapped a photo with a camera.
Back then, film cameras were used.
That's right. I brought something.
- It's a bit embarrassing. - What are those?
What are those?
I brought these.
I printed out these photos.
The resolution is bad...
because I scanned them.
- This is... - Here are your friends.
You're here.
- My goodness. - Here.
My friends.
Dae Ho.
Everyone's photo was taken that day.
(Grade 5, Classroom 3, 1995)
- That's the teacher in the middle. - Yes.
He hasn't changed at all since that day.
Seriously. He looks the same.
I guess he has a good heart.
- There were so many students. - You look exactly the same.
You see me that way. I guess I look the same then.
- That's right. - You look like a fellow teacher.
- Exactly. - A fellow teacher.
(It's hard to see the difference in age.)
Mr. Park doesn't have gray hair.
The ladies we saw earlier are Dae Ho's alumni.
- Yes. - He's Dae Ho's fellow teacher.
Hey, only you've aged.
In the beginning...
- There you are. - I'm not smiling.
Your facial expression was like that.
I didn't smile much.
You weren't attached to a place since you moved around a lot.
- That's right. - I think I was like that.
(The photos bring back memories.)
I remember him.
- Hyeon Dong Ho. - Yes.
- Jung Seok. - Yes.
I remember him too.
I think I know everyone.
(Looking at the photos makes him emotional again.)
- I remember him too. - Yes.
I still remember a lot from those days.
When I look at their faces...
You'll never forget such things.
Dae Ho, how do you still look the same?
This photo.
- Whenever I saw you on TV... - I've had 1 photo for 30 years.
I haven't looked this handsome in my life.
It's the best photo.
(You're ridiculous.)
You know,
it's a bit embarrassing, but I wrote a letter.
- I wrote a letter. - My goodness.
Dae Ho wrote it in advance.
(Hesitant)
Thank you.
I don't have good handwriting.
It's a bit embarrassing, but may I read it for you?
That's something I can't do.
"Dear Mr. Park Jeom Seok."
"Mr. Park, you must be surprised by this sudden visit."
"In my memories,"
"you always talked to me and paid attention to me..."
"when I was alone."
"Many months..."
"after transferring to a new school,"
"I realized that you had sent a letter on my behalf."
"I kept it on my mind in order to deliver my gratitude..."
"and visited you through this good opportunity."
"Although we don't share many memories,"
"our time together is an essential piece in my life."
"That was why I reached out to you despite the fear of appearing rude."
"Thank you for filling up my life."
"So that I can be a shining piece..."
"in your life,"
"I will live diligently."
"Thank you for being my teacher."
"Please stay healthy and happy."
"From your student, Kim Dae Ho."
My goodness.
Mr. Park, thank you so much.
(My Dae Ho)
Mr. Park.
(Hugging)
- This is a tearjerker. - Seriously.
You visited with a big gift.
- Thank you so much. - I'm more grateful.
All right.
I'll keep in touch from now on.
Okay.
(My goodness)
- I'm sorry, everyone. - What?
- Why are you apologizing? - Don't be.
(Looking around)
What's...
- I mean... - What's up with this atmosphere?
Please read the room.
I just don't understand.
- Just be quiet. - Each one...
- Each one feels differently. - That's right.
(I see!)
It's the best gift.
Whenever the Teachers' Day comes,
I say to my students,
"My favorite gift is a letter."
"I understand the emotions this letter contains."
After 30 years, you wrote me a letter.
I'm so sorry that it's short.
It wasn't a long letter,
but I made sure to put my sincerity into it.
I couldn't hold back the tears then.
It seemed like he was saying, "You did well."
At that moment...
- He went back to the past. - Yes.
I thought, "I finally met my teacher."
I'll cherish it.
Thank you so much.
Mr. Park.
I also brought a gift.
It's really small.
It's nothing.
- Thank you. - I found it on my way here.
(He picks up food after delivering what he prepared.)
(My goodness)
My heart feels light.
Please give them to us.
- Happy family and chili shrimp. - Okay.
- The food is served. - The food is served.
(Dishes fill the table.)
- He ordered a lot. - It's nice.
Thank you.
(Chinese dishes fill the table.)
Happy family. He ordered many dishes.
Please taste a little bit of each.
How many servings did you order?
I don't know. I ordered the dishes...
without thinking.
You did well.
Seriously. So many memories are flooding back.
Please eat a lot, Mr. Park.
(Glancing over)
(The food tastes better since it's from Dae Ho.)
- You ordered various dishes. - That's right.
(Proud)
By the way,
you aren't planning to continue living alone,
are you?
Of course not. I'm not celibate.
But if I get hung up...
on the idea of marriage,
my life won't be fun.
So I plan to let things happen naturally.
- Who knows where my fated one is? - That's right.
- I'll meet people. - I hope you'll meet people.
- That's right. - People.
It has been so long since I dated someone.
It has been over nine years.
Around next year, you'll become...
- even more popular. - My goodness.
I'll work even harder.
I'll live diligently so that you can brag about me.
Oh, my.
(Proud)
Each person can influence me in a different way.
I think that's what a teacher does to you.
It's hard to survive in this society.
Society is cutthroat.
After all, you need to take responsibility for everything.
Your life is made up of your choices.
I chose this life,
but the weight of it felt too heavy...
in the past three months.
In some moments, I didn't seem like myself.
There were greed...
and hastiness.
The three months you experience after going freelance...
are like the awkwardness you feel after transferring to a new school.
That must be it.
- I think you're right. - That must be it.
- I had to read the room. - That's the vibe.
- The two instances overlapped. - Yes.
- I guess. - It's natural to remember...
the one who was so good to you.
You're right.
I think that's what a teacher does to you.
He listens to your stories.
He sees my tears without a misunderstanding.
Tears fell down my cheeks.
It was a therapeutic experience.
I think that's the power a teacher has.
A teacher.
When I'm in front of my teacher, I become an elementary schooler.
I'll live diligently.
I bet it was a therapeutic experience.
(To My Turbulent 40s)
(Next story)
(Are these tools waiting for an operation?)
(It takes techniques.)
(My hands are shaking.)
Do you see the roe?
(Roe?)
(I came to see Brother Fish Roe.)
(A workroom in Mount Jiri that's full of the master's secrets)
(I'll teach you everything about fish roe.)
(The first step of becoming Sister Fish Roe)
If it's humid, wipe them twice.
The water is clear in Mount Jiri.
(A 4-month journey to get fish roe of the highest quality)
(Eat a lot.)
(A Mount Jiri meal with 13 side dishes)
(Ground elder, chili leaves, gomchwi, castor aralia shoots,)
(aster scaber, radish greens, bracken)
(The local invigorating food brings happiness to her mouth.)
(A neighbor, Jeon Yu Seong appears.)
(Are there single men who farm by themselves?)
(Many people find a spouse upon moving here.)
(Will she have a blind date in Mount Jiri?)
(She'll make love as well as dried fish roe.)
(A Day That's Full of Roe)
(He carries a plate of fruit...)
(and lies down on the floor.)
(To take care of my health,)
(I came to my parents' place!)
(Recently, I went to the emergency room.)
(Allergy to antibiotics)
(Shortness of breath)
(Aerotitis)
(What should I do?)
(I should rest.)
(I'm hungry.)
(Running down)
(He goes through the fridge in his parents' place.)
(Cold ramyeon is the best for health.)
(If I leave it like that, my mom will take care of it.)
(Happy)
(I love it.)
(Glancing over)
(He grabs a book.)
(Gosh, they're from my golden age.)
(Kim Dong Young's golden age)
(I was a bit of a star.)
(He commanded the playground in his golden age.)
(This place is a must.)
(Successful celebrities from Guri)
(DOYOUNG)
(Eating the love-filled food replenishes his energy.)
(In Body and Mind, I'm Always in My Golden Age)